# **EMILE DURHAM**

Santa Rosa, CA | +17079789600 | durhamemile@gmail.com

## **Professional Summary**

A tech enthusiast interested in pursuing a career that interprets data meaningfully. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in web development and data analysis. Background in health, business and technology. Lived and worked across three different continents. Fluent in English, French and Portuguese (BR).

### Skills

Software programming Web design UX design Instructional design Data analytics Public speaking

### **Technical skills**

- Pvthon
- Django/Flask
- SQL

- Pandas/Numpy
- HTML/CSS
- Git

# **Work History**

**Data Intern** Jun 2020 - Sep 2020 Tallinn, Estonia

Bikeep OÜ

- UX/UI design creating interactive dashboards using Dash
- Data cleaning and basic analysis with MySQL and Python
- Geospatial data analytics of bike parking locations

### **Management Assistant**

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019 Triumf Health Tallinn, Estonia

- Involved with product development and UI testing of mobile therapeutic game
- Contacting potential clients and stakeholder involvement follow-up
- Created and updated physical records and digital files to maintain current, accurate and compliant documentation
- Responsible for updating translated documents, databases and website to reflect modern English usage

### **Marketing/Business Consulting Intern**

InHouse Creative + Sales

Jan 2017 - May 2017 Healdsburg, California

- Gathered, documented and modeled data to assess business trends
- Compiled research data and gave professional presentations highlighting finds and recommended optimizations
- Resolved customer problems, improved operations and provided exceptional client support

**Language Instructor** Aug 2014 - Dec 2014 Itajubá, Brazil

Speaking Idiomas

- Provided French and English instruction to university students and engineering firm employees
- Responsible for developing student assessment methods and instructional design
- Employed diverse teaching approaches to help students of all abilities understand material

### **Education**

**Bootcamp: Full-Stack Python** 09/2020 Software Development Academy Tallinn, Estonia 311 hours

**Master of Science: Health Food Innovation Management** 01/2019 Maastricht University Venlo, NL

**Bachelor of Arts: International Studies** 12/2016 University Of Oregon Eugene, OR